青柳監視官　応答してください
Inspector Aoyanagi, come in.
Inspector Aoyanagi!
青柳監視官
ここの薬は　君たちの色相の濁りを抑えてくれる
The medicine you get here
keeps your Hue under control.
だが同時に　生きている実感を奪っていくんだ
But at the same time, it gradually takes
the feeling of being alive away from you.
私が　偽りの癒やしから君たちを解放する
I will free you
from this false cure...
鹿矛囲のように
...just like Kamui does.
私に便宜を図っておいて　損はないぞ
I'll make it worth
your while to help me.
I'll put in a good word for you
at the Ministry of Welfare.
厚生省にも　口添えをしてやる
だから　早く鹿矛囲を呼んでくれ
So, call Kamui in now!
霜月監視官は　そのまま増田代議士の連行をお願い
Inspector Shimotsuki, please bring
Representative Masuda here.
聴取は私が担当します
I'll do the interrogation.
鹿矛囲の実在を疑う者には任せられないってことですか
Is that because
you can't let someone
who doubts the existence
of Kamui do it?
現場に残された証拠を基に　聴取すべきだからよ
It's because we should question him
based on the evidence left at the scene.
了解しました
Understood.
偶然とは思えないが　確たる証拠がなければ
It's hard to think that it's a coincidence,
but we need some hard evidence...
Otherwise, we'll just make
the same mistake we did with Kitazawa.
また　喜汰沢のときの　二の舞いだぞ
見てください
Look at this... the space where
the impact absorber was removed...
インパクト・アブソーバーが外されたこのスペース
人間一人を収納するには　ちょうどいいサイズだと思いませんか
Don't you think that a person
could easily fit in there?
ドローンは　現場から２ｋｍほど離れた所で発見された
The Drone was found about
two kilometers away from the crime scene.
ドローンの誤作動は　ごくまれにある
Although it's quite rare,
Drones can malfunction.
これが人為的なら　記録に残るはずだが
If the problem was caused by humans,
there should be a record, but...
鹿矛囲は…
It means that Kamui has a way
of tampering with a Drone's logs.
ドローンの記録を改ざんする手段の持ち主ということになります
あくまで実在することが前提か
So you're sticking to this assumption
that he exists, huh?
捜査に賛同できませんか？
You can't support
this investigation?
いや　気が済むまで付き合うさ
No, I'll play along
until you're satisfied.
これは計画的な行動です
This was planned.
私たちが確証を得られず迷っている隙に
While we're trying to dig up
some decisive proof,
鹿矛囲は動き続けているはず
Kamui is still out there
making his next move.
だから　私は疑わない
So... I don't doubt it.
鹿矛囲は　実在する
Kamui really exists.
奪われ続けるなら
If I keep having things taken away from me, I'm gonna lose my mind
Ubaware tsuzukeru nara mou kurutte shimau yo
奪われ続けるなら
もう狂ってしまうよ
This endless "end" will make me stop breathing
Owari no nai "owari" ni boku wa iki wo shinaku natte
終わりの無い「終わり」に僕は息をしなくなって
Enigmatic Feeling
Enigmatic feeling
Why do they have to take things away from me? I'm about to fall apart
Ubawanakya ikenai no? Mou hodokete shimau yo
奪わなきゃいけないの
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
The world began to melt
Sekai ga tokedashite
もうほどけてしまうよ
世界が溶け出して
神様が降りて来て
God descended to confront and ask me
Kami-sama ga orite kite boku ni tsukitsuketa
神様が降りて来て
僕に突きつけた
"Who are you?"
Who are you?
I freed myself by walking in the divide of this world broken into two
Futatsu ni wakareta sekai ni sotte jibun wo hanatta
２つに分かれた世界に沿って
自分を放った
Is there only one God in such a fine borderline?
Kamihitoe darou kamihitoe darou kyoukaisen kami wa hitori na no?
紙一重だろう　紙一重だろう
境界線　神は１人なの
I'm gonna lose my mind, I'm gonna lose my mind...
Okashiku natte okashiku natte
おかしくなって おかしくなって
Suddenly I'll find myself taking you away
Fui ni kimi wo ubatte shimau no darou
ふいに君を奪ってしまうのだろう
Crazy! Crazy!
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Crazy Crazy　完全浮遊体
Because my heart can't focus
Pinto no awanai kokoro ni
ピントの合わない心に
Shake me! Shake me!
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I'm completely adrift
Kanzen fuyuutai
Shake me Shake me　完全浮遊体
I can't even look into the mirror
Kagami sae mo nozokenai
鏡さえも覗けない
#4: The Salvation of Job
No luck. I am unable to access neither
their security cameras nor scanners.
駄目ね
監視カメラにも　スキャナーにも　アクセスできない
The entire building is dead.
建物全体が死んでるわね
Has something like this
happened in the past?
過去に　そ　んな例は？
The only cases I can think of
are big disasters, like a fire...
考えられるのは大きな災害
例えば　火事
This doesn't exactly
fit the bill, though.
そんなふうには見えないけど
Hey...
おい　エリアストレスが　注意報域まで上昇したぞ
The Area Stress has gone up
to the advisory range.
What's the Inspector doing?
監視官は　何をしているんだ
This is the natural you,
the way you were born.
それが　君たちの生まれたままの姿だ
Do you feel the joy
of being alive?
感じるかね　生きている喜びを
That's right.
そうだ　いいぞ…
Good.
I understand
your pain all too well.
君たちのつらさは　よく分かる
Rather than having your mind healed,
you're on the verge of being killed
誤った処方で　心を癒やされるどころか
due to the wrong medication.
殺される寸前なのだから
Let the stress in... It's the proof
that we are alive in this world.
ストレスを受け入れろ　この世界に生きている証しを
Feel! Feel the pain!
Feel your heart beating! Feel your life!
感じたまえ　苦痛を　命の鼓動を　君の人生を
嫌っ…
It's so great to be alive.
生きてるって　素晴らしいね
Let's request assistance.
応援を要請しよう
In any event, we can't do anything
without having an Inspector here.
いずれにしても　監視官不在では動けない
Yeah, I know.
ああ　分かってる
I'll take care of the assistance request
from Division 2.
二係からの応援要請は　私の方で対処しておきます
Thanks. Considering the timing,
please handle the situation with care.
お願い　タイミングがタイミングだから
注意して　処理に当たって
This isn't a big deal.
大したことありませんよ
I'm sure people who got
trapped inside just panicked.
閉じ込められた人たちが　パニックに陥っただけでしょ
It's true that it's easy
for confusion and fear to spread
確かにメンタルケア施設では
混乱や恐怖が　伝染しやすいといわれているけど
within mental care facilities, but...
Do you think that even this is too much
for an unskilled junior Inspector?
不得手な後輩じゃ
この程度でも　手に余る仕事だと思ってますか
What?
You must be quite pleased
気分いいんじゃありませんか　先輩は
now that someone else
mentioned Kamui, right?
鹿矛囲がいるって証言者が増えて
It's rather the opposite.
むしろ逆よ
Thanks for bringing him in.
Leave the rest to me.
連行ご苦労さま　後は任せて
You be careful, too.
そっちも気を付けてね
You're confident, aren't you...?
余裕ですね
A mental care facility...
Why would Aoyanagi go to a place like that?
メンタルケア施設　なぜ青柳はそんな場所に…
I don't know, but let's focus
on the interrogation for now.
分からない
今は　聴取に集中しましょう
Thank you for your cooperation,
Representative Kotoku Masuda.
ご協力　感謝します　増田幸徳代議士
Who is Kamui?
鹿矛囲とは　何者ですか
I don't know anyone like that.
そんなやつは知らない
I heard that you said
to call Kamui in.
「鹿矛囲を呼んでくれ」
あなたは　そうおっしゃっていたそうですね
I don't remember.
記憶にない
In order to keep
your Psycho-Pass clear,
あなたは　サイコパスをクリアに保つため
you relied on someone
named Kamui.
鹿矛囲という人物に頼っていた
How did you communicate with him?
Where did you get in touch with him?
鹿矛囲とは　どのように連絡を？
どこで　コンタクトを取っていたんですか？
So suddenly he's got
nothing to say?
いまさら黙秘か
This is strange...
おかしい…
Don't move.
動かないで
Wh-What're you doing?
な…何してるの？
I'm sorry. I've been
ordered to... by that man.
すいません　命令されて…　あの人に
嫌…嫌…
You are all alive!
Everyone... Everyone is alive!
君たちは　生きている
みんな　みんな生きているんだ
Life is wonderful.
人生は　素晴らしい
This is terrible...
ひどい…
No, don't move.
駄目よ
動かないで
But...
でも…
Don't worry.
Trust me.
大丈夫　信じて
I'll save everyone
without fail...
必ず全員助ける
...because that's my job.
それが　私の仕事だから
What's going on?
状況は？
We still don't know
what's going on inside the facility.
依然　施設内の状況は不明のまま
There haven't been any reports
of incidents in this area,
周囲で事件の通報はありませんが
but the Area Stress
keeps going up.
エリアストレスは上昇する一方です
It's almost certain that
this place is the source.
ここが現場なのはほぼ間違いありませんね
Why don't we force it open
from the outside?
外からこじ開けては？
No, in this case, we need to check
the cause of the stress first.
いえ　この場合　ストレスの原因を調べるのが先です
If we carelessly release them,
the situation can get worse.
うかつに解放すれば
さらに悪化する可能性もありますから
So our only option is to find a way
to communicate with people inside.
やはり　内部と連絡を取る手段を　探すしか…
I narrowed the Area Stress check down
to just the area around this building.
エリアストレスの予想範囲をこの建物周辺に絞ってみたんですが…
Look at this.
見てくださいよ
It's way over the warning line.
余裕で　警報域だ
I wouldn't be surprised even if everyone
in there was a target for enforcement.
これじゃ　執行対象だらけになっててもおかしくない
Someone else mentioned Kamui's name.
And one of the Drones
また新たに鹿矛囲の名が出ました
そして　爆弾解体ドローンの移動と部品損失
sent to defuse the bombs was moved
and was missing a part...
This could be a breakthrough
for the Devil's Proof...
それらが　悪魔の証明の突破口になる
Is that what you're
trying to say?
そう言いたいのか？
The man who was brought in
knows something.
連行された人物は　何かを知っている
Could you help me, Mr. Saiga?
力を貸していただけませんか　先生
I want to be a savior!
私は　救世主になりたいんだ！
I want to save people,
just like Kamui does.
救いたいんだよ
鹿矛囲のように
そこまでよ
Stop right there!
So this representative
named Masuda...
増田とかいう代議士
色相が濁ったのは講演会での演説前だった
His Hue got clouded
before his speech.
There's no mistake about it?
それは　間違いないな？
Right.
And after his speech,
はい　そして演説後
he was taken into custody
by Inspector Shimotsuki.
霜月監視官により　身柄を拘束されています
It's often the case
that people like that
そういう手合いは…
consistently have their Hue worsen
under the same circumstances.
常に同じ状況下で色相が悪化するケースが多い
Check the days he gave a speech
over the past several months.
ここ数カ月の講演会の日程を　洗ってみろ
His phone records, too.
あとは　通話履歴だ
A savior?
Don't make me laugh.
何が救世主よ
You're a crazy latent criminal.
Either give yourself up now and go to a facility
いかれた潜在犯は　おとなしく施設に入るか
or receive
an enforcement action here.
ここで　執行されなさい
「犯罪係数　７６」
Crime Coefficient is 76.
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありません」
Trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
Why?!
どうして
いいぞ　その調子だ
Good.
Keep it up.
But you should understand
what I'm saying a little better.
しかし　もう少し私の言うことを理解した方がいい
Dammit...
Why... is this...
チクショー…
Crime Coefficient is 112.
He is a target for enforcement action.
どうしてこんな…
「犯罪係数　１１２」
「執行対象です」
No! Not him!
違う…　彼じゃない
I detect the operation
of a Dominator.
ドミネーターの作動を確認
使用者は…　青柳監視官？
Is the user... Inspector Aoyanagi?
There is a target for enforcement inside.
What should we do?
中に執行対象者がいます　どうしますか？
Nothing.
どうもしないわよ
We'll await contact
from Inspector Aoyanagi.
青柳監視官からの連絡を待ちます
It'll be my fault if we act on our own
and something goes wrong.
勝手に動いて　何かあったら　私の責任になるじゃない
分析室からの返答　届きました
We received a response
from the Analysis Lab.
They identified the device
Representative Masuda was contacting
増田代議士が講演会前日に毎回連絡を取っていた端末を特定
the day before
each of his speeches.
Who's the user?
使用者は？
That is unknown,
不明ですが　端末の現在位置は…
but the device is currently
at the mental care facility in Shibuya Ward.
渋谷区　メンタルケア施設です
The place where Division 2
requested assistance?
二係が　応援を要請した現場だと？
Kamui... is there!
そこに　鹿矛囲が…
Inspector Aoyanagi. We're currently
standing by in front of the facility.
青柳監視官　現在われわれは施設前で待機しています
Please report
what's going on inside.
現場の状況を報告してください
To those who use force to suppress
those trying to live healthy lives!
健やかに生きる者を力で抑圧する者たちよ
Heed my words!
私の言葉を聞きたまえ
What?!
何
私は知っているのだ
I know what becomes of those
who have all their stress taken from them
誤った処方により　一切のストレスが消えた
by taking the wrong medication.
人間の成れの果てを
Eustress deficiency...
ユーストレス欠乏症
I stopped being affected by stimuli,
and I felt numb inside.
あらゆる刺激が消え　無感覚に冒された私は
I was about to give up
on my own life.
己の命まで　自ら捨てるところだった
I will denounce the reality
of frightening mental care
私は告発する
生きる喜びを奪う　恐ろしいメンタルケアの実態を
that takes the joy of living
away from people.
And then, I will save people...
just like Kamui saved me.
そして　人々を救うのだ
私を救った　鹿矛囲のように
Kamui?!
鹿矛囲？
また…
Not again... Is this some shared delusion
by crazy people or something?!
いかれてる人たちの共同幻想か　何かなわけ？
He's even bringing up a stupid
urban legend like eustress deficiency.
ユーストレス欠乏症なんてくだらない都市伝説まで持ち出して…
An urban legend...
都市伝説…
Did you hear back
from Inspector Aoyanagi?
青柳監視官からの返信は？
まだない
Not yet, despite the fact
that she came online once.
一度　オンラインになったのに…
施設内の全員が　今の声の男に拘束されている可能性もあるのでは？
Isn't it possible that the man
we just heard has restrained everyone?
If that's the case, we should subdue him
and rescue them right away.
なら　すぐに制圧と救助を
But we haven't received
such a request yet.
でも　そんな要請は　受けてないし…
また　鹿矛囲の名前か
Kamui again.
What the hell is going on?
いったい　どうなっている
Hinakawa, come in.
雛河君　応答して
あ…　あっ　はい
Y-Y-Yes.
Check and see if there's anyone
with a Holo on around there.
現場周辺に　ホロをまとった　人物がいないか調べて
A Holo...
What kind?
ホロ…　どんな？
I don't know if it's the same woman
in Kitazawa's case or a different one.
喜汰沢のときの女性か
別の姿か分からない
きっと　雛河君にしか　見極められない
I bet you're the only one
who can uncover it. Please!
お願い
わ…分かりました
O-Okay.
I see. Considering that the Holo we saw
was made abnormally elaborate,
なるほど
異常なほど　精巧なホロを作ることから
it's highly likely that Kamui
is strongly obsessed with Holo.
鹿矛囲は　ホロに強い執着を　持っている可能性が高い
Like the clothes
ghosts would wear?
透明人間が着る服のようにか？
全てが　鹿矛囲の計画なら　目的は何？
If this is all Kamui's plan,
then what's his goal?
Why is he going this far?
どうして　ここまでするの？
No, he's not here.
違う
いない
No, he's not here.
違う
いない
No... No...
違う
Hey! What're you doing?!
ちょっと
何やってるの？
つ…常守監視官のめ…命令で
I-I got an order from...
I-Inspector Tsunemori.
Don't act on your own.
I'm the commander here.
余計なことしないで
現場指揮官は私でしょ
でも…
But...
ここは三係が預かる
We, Division 3,
will take over the case.
Follow our instructions.
こちらの指示に従ってくれ
そんな…
What?! Under what
authority do you...
何の権限があって
These are Chief Kasei's orders.
We'll immediately start the enforcement.
禾生局長の命令だ
直ちに　執行を開始する
Chief Kasei took me off?
Why...?
禾生局長が　私を外した？
何で…
Yes, that's right.
Scatter the crowd
ああ　そうだ
やじ馬は散らし　報道各社も現場に立ち入らせないように
and don't let any media organizations
enter the area.
It'll be a problem
ユーストレス欠乏症などと事実無根な妄言が流布されるのは問題だ
if a groundless delusion
such as eustress deficiency is spread...
...though no one in this society
would believe such a delusion.
そもそも　そんな妄言を信じる人間がこの社会に存在するはずもないがね
There's one common thread
between the first case and this one.
最初の事件との共通点が一つ
They separated an Inspector
from her team and isolated her.
監視官を引き離し　孤立させること
Kamui's targeting Inspectors?
狙いは　監視官？
Or maybe not Inspectors
themselves, but...
もしくは　監視官自身ではなく…
Dominators instead.
ドミネーター…
普通ならあり得ないけど
Under normal circumstances,
it wouldn't be possible,
but it may not have been Inspector Shisui
who shot Enforcer Yamatoya.
山門屋執行官を撃ったのは酒々井監視官では　ないのかもしれない
Kamui did...?
鹿矛囲が…
Someone unapproved
somehow used the Dominator.
適正のない人間が何らかの手段でドミネーターを扱った
That case itself
was an experiment for that...
あの事件そのものがそのための実験だった…
That's enough, Tsunemori!
もういいかげんにしろ　常守
お前のサイコパスが濁るぞ
Your Psycho-Pass
will get clouded!
A ghost... Even if we can't see them,
we can still follow their trail.
透明人間…
姿は見えなくても　残された足跡を追うことはできる
Okay, commence operation!
よし　開始しろ
The MWPSB... how foolish...
公安局め…　くだらんことを
I am... an Inspector.
私は…　監視官…
Elevated Area Stress Level
Special Warning issued
An elevated Area Stress Level
special warning...!
エリアストレス上昇特別警報…
こりゃ　中のやつらはサイコパス保ってらんねえな
There's no way that those inside
can keep their Psycho-Pass stable.
実験…
An experiment... Kamui is trying
to learn how to use a Dominator.
鹿矛囲は　ドミネーターの使い方を知ろうとしている
But he's already
shot one Enforcer.
それなら　すでに執行官を一人撃っている
If being surrounded by MWPSB officers
was also within his calculation,
公安局員に包囲されるのも　計算づくなら
his goal this time
isn't for he himself to shoot.
今回の目的は　自分が撃つことじゃない
Are you saying that his goal
is to have someone else shoot then?
誰かを撃たせることが　目的だって言うのか？
With such a roundabout way of doing things,
who the hell is he trying to...
そんな回りくどいことをして　いったい誰を…
人と法を守るために
In order to protect people
and the law, I will...
私は　お前を…！
壁越しに撃った？
They shot through the wall...?
That's the MWPSB's new armament,
the Assault Dominator.
あれが　公安の新兵装
強襲型ドミネーターだ
When walls hinder access to the crime scene,
we can rely on that.
外壁に阻まれた現場では　こいつが頼りになる
Looks like it went
extremely well.
首尾は上々のようだな
上々？
Extremely well?
When you did something that can stress out
エリミネーターが　発動するほど
施設内の人々の心的負荷を高めるようなまねをしておいてですか？
the people inside so severely
as to trigger Eliminator mode?
Ms. Kunizuka...
六合塚さん…
俺は　命令に従っているだけだ
I'm just following orders.
There's no mistake that
the person you shot was the culprit?
仕留めたのは　犯人で　間違いないな？
I don't know. I just shot the one
with the higher Crime Coefficient.
分かりません
犯罪係数が高い方を　執行しただけです
助けて
- Help!
- We are the victims!
俺たちは　被害者だ
Crime Coefficient is 322.
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「犯罪係数　３２２」
「執行モード　リーサル・エリミネーター」
What the hell is this number?!
何だ　この数値…
「執行モード　リーサル・エリミネーター」
Enforcement mode
is Lethal Eliminator.
Everyone is a target for enforcement action!
Don't let them escape!
全員　執行対象だ！　逃がすな！
How terrible...
Inspector Shimotsuki!
こんな…
霜月監視官
だって…　もう　これは　一係の事件じゃない
What can I do?
This case no longer belongs to Division 1.
We have nothing to do with it.
私たちには　関係ない…
Stop it!
やめろ！
What are you... doing?!
お前たち…
何をやっている！
I now know the answer.
答えは得た
Inspectors can also be judged
by the Dominators.
監視官もまたドミネーターで裁くことができる
Thank you.
ありがとう
君のおかげで　僕たちはまた一つ先に進めた
Thanks to you, we were able
to move a step forward.
行こう　逃げ道は用意してある
Let's go.
I have our escape route ready.
I wonder what color I am now.
私は　今　何色なんだろうか…
When I met you,
君と出会ったときの私は
I was a living corpse who had lost
the color of life due to eustress deficiency.
ユーストレス欠乏症で　命の色彩を失った
生ける　しかばねだった
But I'm different now.
I was finally able to get my existence back.
しかし　今の私は違う
やっと　自分の存在を　取り戻せた
Please let me stay here.
このまま　ここに　いさせてくれ
This is all I could do.
私にできるのは　この程度だった…
You can change the world.
I'm glad that I've met you, Kamui.
君なら　世界を変えられる
会えてよかったよ　鹿矛囲
ありがとう
Thank you.
見えているか　僕たちが流す血の色が
Can you see it...
...the color of the blood we shed?
Why don't you tell me...
what color we are?
僕たちが何色か
答えてみろ
Can't be...
Aoyanagi...
嘘だろ…
青柳…
Inspector Tsunemori!
常守監視官
これは　この社会の全てに問い掛けているのかもしれない
This question may be directed
towards all of society.
All of society?
全て？
Asking each of us to question
our color... and also...
自分は何色か
そして…
シビュラ　お前は何色だ？
Sibyl... what color are you?
All is calm, all is bright
All is calm All is bright
A whispering fallen angel
Sasayaku tenshi wa ochite
囁く天使は堕ちて
Gently devours you, body and soul
Yasashiku hamu wa anata no subete o
優しく食むわ　あなたの全てを
It's my guilty
You notice me
Kidzuku
気づく　目を見開いてる
With your eyes wide open,
Me o mihiraiteru
A faint blue as lifeless as concrete
Honoaoi konkuriito
仄青い混凝土
In a cold tone,
Tsumetaku watashi o
冷たく私を
Call my name and give me a kiss
And then hold me in the arms of the empty shell that is your body
Soshite dakishimete anata no inai sono karada de
そして抱きしめて
あなたのいないその体で
That soul that you've cast out
Hakidashita sono inochi wa
吐き出しその生命は
Has not yet completely vanished
Mada katachi o nokoshiteiru wa
まだ形を残しているわ　紅く
I glimpse a vivid red eternity
Akaku azayaka na eien ga miete
鮮やかな永遠が見えて
It starts singing right next to me
Tonari de sore wa utaidasu
隣でそれは歌いだすわ
What was I born for
Come on, love me
Nee watashi o aishite
ねえ　私を愛して
Because I won't let you go
Hanasanai kara
離さないから
Hello my name is
A world where humans' state of mind
and the tendency of their personalities can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed, these measured numbers used to judge people's souls
are commonly called 'Psycho-Pass.'
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations
that appear in the show are fictitious,
and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.